Guide to the Lee Kass papers,1989-2001.
Kass, Lee papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lee Kass papers, 1989-2001.
6520
Lee B., Kass 1946-
11 cubic ft.
Manuscripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files relating to her career, to her teaching at Elmira College, and to a sexual discrimination lawsuit.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Botanist.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files relating to her career, to her teaching at Elmira College, and to a sexual discrimination lawsuit.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kass, Lee B.,1946-; Elmira College.
Subjects:
Sex discrimination in employment.; Women in education.; Women college teachers.; Botanists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of donor.
CONTAINER LIST
- Not all the material in the collection is covered by this guide.
  - Files to Mimi's, June 13, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Gale: "Similarly Situated Male Faculty, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Satter and Andrews, LLP Letter to Gale, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Legal Comeop-EEOC, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Interrogatories of Gale and Kass EEOC, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Discovery Inventory and Inventory, Jan.2, 2000, Mar. 18, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Magistrate's Order, March 30, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - EOC Statistical Analysis, Nov. 6, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Division Chair Memos on Salary-Merit and Stalting, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Division Char Memos on Salary, Merit and Stalting, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - H.R., 1993 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - H.R., 1992 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - H.R., 1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - #21, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - EC Letter Response Settlement Negotiations, Nov. 30, 1999- Feb. 6 2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Reddick: Merit-Salary Input, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Response to Interrogation of DI Gale, Feb.-March 1999 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Discovery, Nov. 1999 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - EC Answer and Final Complaint EEOC, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Title IX Self Study, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - DHR Complaint Administrative Dismissal, July 6, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - EEO Interrogation and Draft Complaint, March 16, 1999 and June-July, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - EEOC E-Mails, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Memos of C Drive, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - EEOC, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - EEO Schedule, Nov-Dec. 1999 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Deposition Questions and Ducuments. Gale Letter., March 11, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Letter From Ben Otten, May 22, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - CRS Program, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Criminal Justice Majors and Enrollment, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Criminal Justice Club, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Criminal Justice Club, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Paul Kish, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - H.R. Memos Not Sent, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Memoranda, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Orientation Memos, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Letters and E-Mails, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - EC, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - CRJ/SOC Mess, 1997-2000 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - EEOC-98 CV 1057. D1,2 Gale, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - EEOC I #1, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - I #2, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - I #3, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - I #4, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - I #5, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - I #6 Right to Sue Documents in hue EEOC, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - I #7, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - I #8, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - I #9, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - EEOC Misc. Doc., 1998 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Copies of I's sent., Jan. 16, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - E.C. Classes, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - CRJ Budget, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Searen Committee CRJ/SOC, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - CRJ Budget, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - E.C. Soc. Sciences Divi., 1999 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Division Schedules, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Division, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - E-mails to Case, Feb. 2000 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - EOC Depositions: DHR, Witness Hist., Schedule., March. 2000 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - DHR Administrative Dismissed, July 6, 1998 and July 14, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - DI Witness, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Term 111 Leave Memos, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - EEO, May-June, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Produce Documents 14, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Produce Documents 13, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - I #23, Jan. 16, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - I #22, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - I #21, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - I #20, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - I #19, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - I #18, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - I #17, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - I #16, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - I #15, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - I #14, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - I #13, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - I #12, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - I #11, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - I #10, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Non Economic Harm Note., 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Appendix K.G.B., 1991 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Miscellaneous EEOC (ii), 1998 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Miscellaneous EEOC (i), 1998 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Dean's Memos and DHR, Aug. 1996-1998 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - EEOC. Berg Correspondence, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Schedule as Modified, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Jerry Gapp, Reddick Memo sent on advice of R. Brown, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Various E-Mails, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Correspondence and Reviews of Major. Soc. Science CRJ, 1987-1991. 1986-2000 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Genetics course, 1982-2000 (Box 12, Folder 1-34)
  - Backgrounds and frontiers in modern biological science, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Phone contacts from Elmira College, 1995, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Plant Morphology, 1984-1994 (Box 12, Folder 37-41)
  - Evolution, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 42-43)
  - Horticulture, 1982; 1985 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Plant Anatomy, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Plant Anatomy, 1978-1998 (Box 13, Folder 1-22)
  - Save the Rainforest, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 23-25)
  - World of plants, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Plant Physiology, 1978-2000 (Box 13, Folder 27-28)
  - Basic Biological Concepts Lecture and Labs, 1982-1999 (Box 13, Folder 30-32)
  - Basic Biological Concepts Labs and Activities, 1995; 1979 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Field Botany, 1985; 1987 (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
  - Field Biology, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Biology of the Environment, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
  - Guest Lecture Pollination, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Workshop at Grace Episcopal Church, Elmira, NY, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - CORE 2000 (Medieval and Renaissance) and slides plus note for Alchemy Lecture (Box 14, Folder 12-14)
  - Fulbright Scholar, College of the Bahamas, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 15-26)
  - Graduate Student at Cornell, notebooks, 1971-1975 (Box 14, Folder 27-33)
  - Graduate Student at Cornell, correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 14, Folder 34-38)
  - Correspondence with research collaborator Beverly Rathcke, University of Michigan, 2005-2007 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Cornell calendars, 1996-2007 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Field Trip [Meeting] Notes, 1982-2001 (Box 15, Folder 2-20)
  - Correspondence, 1983-2002 (Box 15, Folder 21-35)
  - Fulbright Application, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Costa Rica, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - Women's Rights Park Opening, program and LBK photos, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Josef Stein Award to LBK, photos, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Northrop research paper published 2005, 2002-2005 (Box 16, Folder 6-16)
  - Ethics in science paper published 2001, 1995-2001 (Box 16, Folder 17-22)
  - Michigan Hollow litigation, expert witness, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
  - Miscellany, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Litigation files RESTRICTED, 1993-2000 (Box 16, Folder 26-28)
  - Litigation files RESTRICTED, 1982-2000 (Box 17-18)